<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ink language docs on .ink</title>
    <link>https://dotink.co/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ink language docs on .ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dotink.co/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Ink? Ink is a functional, general-purpose, interpreted scripting language. It&amp;rsquo;s dynamically and strongly typed. Ink programs can be web servers, short scripts, drawing programs, or anything else that interfaces with files and networks. Ink is designed to be minimal and simple, first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-source Ink projects</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Traceur Traceur is a path-tracing renderer in Ink, supporting Monte-Carlo antialiasing, realistic shadows, reflections, refractions, and focus blur.
Blog post See on GitHub →
Klisp Klisp is a very minimal LISP written in Ink. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily a pedagogical project &amp;ndash; I made it to understand Lisp better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtime and builtins</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</guid>
      <description>Operating system interfaces Many system interface builtin functions are designed around asynchronous callbacks, and will return an event object to a callback function in response. Such an event object is of a semi-standard form, on success</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard library reference</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</guid>
      <description>The Ink standard library is not current packaged into the distributed binary. However, you can get up-to-date versions of these libraries on GitHub.
Standard (std) std is Ink&amp;rsquo;s core library.
See source on GitHub →
log(val) Prints the string version of val to standard output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>