<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ink blog on .ink</title>
    <link>https://dotink.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Ink blog on .ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dotink.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing pi as a Riemann sum</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/pi-by-riemann-sum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:08:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/pi-by-riemann-sum/</guid>
      <description>While researching the difference between Intel&amp;rsquo;s various x86 SIMD extensions, I came across this article that demonstrates SSE and AVX performance differences using an algorithm to compute an approximation of pi using a Riemann sum under a curve. Specifically, we can numerically compute the integral
$$\int_{0}^{1} \frac{4}{1 + x^2} \mathrm{d} x = 4 \tan ^{-1} (x) = \pi $$
to find a reasonably quickly converging approximation of \( \pi \). This approach to approximating pi was novel to me, and seemed fun, so wrote a little Ink script to compute the integrals numerically for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;m learning about in sales</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/sales-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/sales-learnings/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
As I&amp;rsquo;m diving deeper into my role at Hack Club Bank, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn more about sales and working with customers, and I&amp;rsquo;m also learning a lot every week about leading a B2B product. This is a place for me to collect the things I&amp;rsquo;m learning in the process. I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep this up to date over time, and I thought it would be nice to make it publicly available, in case you might find it useful as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Repl.it, Hello Hack Club</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/composing-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/composing-the-future/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
Summer&amp;rsquo;s almost over! It&amp;rsquo;s a change of season, and the season of changes.
My internship at Repl.it is coming to a close, and I&amp;rsquo;m joining the fantastic team at Hack Club moving forward. I wanted to take a moment to talk about what I learned at Repl.it, and why I&amp;rsquo;m so excited about Hack Club.
Repl.it: building for builders Today was my last day as an engineering intern at Repl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and exploring sorting algorithms in two dimensions with Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/visualizing-sorting-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/visualizing-sorting-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Until Elon Musk brings his Neuralink gadgets to market, our eyes are the highest-bandwidth way we have of understanding the world around us. We can look at something and immediately take in the hues, the lightness and the darkness, the shapes, and most importantly, the patterns that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to notice if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t use our vision.
In fact, our eyes are surprisingly good at pattern recognition, noticing the rhythm in the details that make up the large-scale structure of what&amp;rsquo;s in front of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I side project</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/how-i-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/how-i-side-project/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
This post started out as a long-form response to this tweet by Raj Kunkolienkar:
Question to all the side project machines that I follow (with much respect) : what framework / setup / infrastructure / tools do you use to push out ideas to MVP so quickly?@kognise @thesephist @jajoosam
&amp;mdash; Raj Kunkolienkar 🚀 (@kunksed) May 21, 2019  &amp;hellip; but then, I got busy, a few weeks passed, and it took a while for me to get back to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Ink? Ink is a functional, general-purpose, interpreted scripting language. It&amp;rsquo;s dynamically and strongly typed. Ink programs can be web servers, short scripts, drawing programs, or anything else that interfaces with files and networks. Ink is designed to be minimal and simple, first and foremost.
I made Ink as an experiment to study writing interpreters and compilers in mid-2019. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on several other related projects in the programming language space, but continue to write programs and apps in Ink in my day to day work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-source Ink projects</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</guid>
      <description>dotink This website is served by a web server written in Ink
See on GitHub →
Polyx Polyx is Linus&amp;rsquo;s personal productivity suite
See on GitHub →
Codeliner Codeliner generates graphics from program source files
See on GitHub →</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtime and builtins</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</guid>
      <description>Operating system interfaces args in out dir make stat read write delete listen req rand urand time wait exec Math builtins sin cos asin acos pow ln floor Runtime introspection functions string number point char type len keys load </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard library reference</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</guid>
      <description>The Ink standard library is not current packaged into the distributed binary. However, you can get up-to-date versions of these libraries on GitHub.
Standard (std) std is Ink&amp;rsquo;s core library.
See source on GitHub →
range(first, second, third) String (str) str contains string manipulation functions.
See source on GitHub →
Sort (quicksort) quicksort contains an implementation of Quicksort using Hoare partition.
See source on GitHub →
UUID (uuid) uuid generates version 4 UUIDs from the rand() builtin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/syntax/</guid>
      <description>// in the style of: http://wren.io/syntax.html
Ink programs are UTF-8 or ASCII text files with the .ink file extension. Ink&amp;rsquo;s syntax takes inspiration from Go and modern JavaScript, and strives to be minimal, concise, unambiguous, and fast to parse.
Comments Ink, like C, has both single- and multi-line comments.
Keywords Commas and automatic comma insertion Grouping Whitespace and indentation Variables and assignment Ink identifiers can start with any alphabetic character and can contain any alphanumeric character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types and interfaces</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/types/</guid>
      <description>Primitive Types Ink has four primitive types:
   The composite interface Ink&amp;rsquo;s string and composite (and there for list) data types both follow the same interface for composite data types. This means that any functions buit around the interface will be correct for strings (including arbitrary blob data), composite dictionaries, and lists. The coposite interface consists of the following operations and functions. Say we have a composite c with string key k.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>