<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ink blog on .ink</title>
    <link>https://dotink.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Ink blog on .ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dotink.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Better terminal output from Ink with ANSI escape codes</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/ansi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:51:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/ansi/</guid>
      <description>ANSI escape codes Most of the time, we think of a computer terminal as a place to output text. We generate logs and print output from programs to the terminal, and interact with the shell by typing lines in and getting lines out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary search for rational approximations of irrational numbers</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/rational-binary-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:32:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/rational-binary-search/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably simple rational approximation of Pi?
We might take a naive approach and simply take a fraction like \(\frac{314159265}{100000000}\) and reduce it to get a fractional representation of an arbitrary decimal form of Pi. But this is boring, and requires large denominators to be precise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notable papers about computing and software</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 13:13:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/papers/</guid>
      <description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time reading papers about computer science and software engineering. I&amp;rsquo;m not in academia, so I don&amp;rsquo;t always read papers in the cutting edge of the field, but I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed reading seminal papers written at the birth of interesting technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traceur: a path tracing renderer in Ink and JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/traceur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 10:12:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/traceur/</guid>
      <description>Traceur (pronounced like trace + connoisseur) is a path tracing renderer written in Ink. Traceur is capable of rendering scenes with spherical objects, realistic shadows, reflections, refractions, and depth of field. Internally, Traceur uses well-defined interfaces for working with shapes, materials, and scene descriptions, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to extend with new textures and lighting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inkfmt: a self-hosting code formatter for Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/inkfmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 17:15:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/inkfmt/</guid>
      <description>inkfmt (pronounced &amp;ldquo;ink format&amp;rdquo; or sometimes &amp;ldquo;ink fuh-mt&amp;rdquo;) is a self-hosting code formatter for the Ink language. This means inkfmt takes valid Ink programs and normalizes the formatting of the code to be readable and clean. inkfmt is itself an Ink program, and inkfmt uses itself to format its own source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I set up my servers</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/unix-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 11:44:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/unix-setup/</guid>
      <description>Many of my projects include a web server, usually written in Go, Node.js, or Ink. I deploy these servers to Linux VMs running on DigitalOcean, and I set them all up very similarly. I currently have 17 separate web servers / projects running across two $5/month servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing pi as a Riemann sum</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/pi-by-riemann-sum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:08:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/pi-by-riemann-sum/</guid>
      <description>While researching the difference between Intel&amp;rsquo;s various x86 SIMD extensions, I came across this article that demonstrates SSE and AVX performance differences using an algorithm to compute an approximation of pi using a Riemann sum under a curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;m learning about in sales</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/sales-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/sales-learnings/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
As I&amp;rsquo;m diving deeper into my role at Hack Club Bank, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn more about sales and working with customers, and I&amp;rsquo;m also learning a lot every week about leading a B2B product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Repl.it, Hello Hack Club</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/composing-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/composing-the-future/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
Summer&amp;rsquo;s almost over! It&amp;rsquo;s a change of season, and the season of changes.
My internship at Repl.it is coming to a close, and I&amp;rsquo;m joining the fantastic team at Hack Club moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and exploring sorting algorithms in two dimensions with Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/visualizing-sorting-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/visualizing-sorting-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Until Elon Musk brings his Neuralink gadgets to market, our eyes are the highest-bandwidth way we have of understanding the world around us. We can look at something and immediately take in the hues, the lightness and the darkness, the shapes, and most importantly, the patterns that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to notice if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t use our vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I side project</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/posts/how-i-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/posts/how-i-side-project/</guid>
      <description>(This is an archived copy of a post originally published at thesephist.com.)
This post started out as a long-form response to this tweet by Raj Kunkolienkar:
Question to all the side project machines that I follow (with much respect) : what framework / setup / infrastructure / tools do you use to push out ideas to MVP so quickly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of Ink</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/overview/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Ink? Ink is a functional, general-purpose, interpreted scripting language. It&amp;rsquo;s dynamically and strongly typed. Ink programs can be web servers, short scripts, drawing programs, or anything else that interfaces with files and networks. Ink is designed to be minimal and simple, first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-source Ink projects</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Traceur Traceur is a path-tracing renderer in Ink, supporting Monte-Carlo antialiasing, realistic shadows, reflections, refractions, and focus blur. I wrote about building Traceur here.
See on GitHub →
Polyx Polyx is Linus&amp;rsquo;s personal productivity suite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtime and builtins</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/runtime/</guid>
      <description>Operating system interfaces Many system interface builtin functions are designed around asynchronous callbacks, and will return an event object to a callback function in response. Such an event object is of a semi-standard form, on success</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard library reference</title>
      <link>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dotink.co/docs/lib/</guid>
      <description>The Ink standard library is not current packaged into the distributed binary. However, you can get up-to-date versions of these libraries on GitHub.
Standard (std) std is Ink&amp;rsquo;s core library.
See source on GitHub →
log(val) Prints the string version of val to standard output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>